

SHIVAM GUPTA

web: imshivamgupta.github.io email: shivamg8797@gmail.com

LinkedIn: imshivamgupta1

phone: +(91) 8090908320, 8979315982

ABOUT ME

Front end Engineer passionate about Technologies, Rendering Performance, Security, Dev Tools, Browser Internals and User Experience.

I focus on Frontend/UI architecture, platform design, performance and building stellar experiences for customer delight using technical insights.

I love to write semantics code with modern styles for better understanding.

SKILLS

HTML5

CSS3

JavaScript (ES6)

SCSS

ReactJS

Adobe Photoshop

Visual Studio Code

Cordova

EXPERIENCE

<u>Terasol Technologies</u>/ Frontend Developer

Jan 2018 - March 2019

- Creating Components/Layout in ReactJS
- Generating dynamic UI by REST API in JSON Format.
- Maintained Client websites on an ongoing basis.
- Designed and Developed Custom WordPress Themes.
- Developing HTML5 pages such dashboards, scorecards and Graphs using JavaScript.
- Making Development plans, work flow and user test cases by providing input to client for good user experience.

Cyberoze/ Web Designer

Sept 2017 - Nov 2017 (Intern)

- Designed and Developed views/template on top of Laravel using Blade template engine.
- Designed logos, banners and ads for client and company for Social Media Campaigns using Adobe Photoshop.

The Story Pedia / Web Designer

May 2017 – July 2017 (Intern)

- Designed static webpages and worked various theme/templates.
- Created Custom WordPress themes and worked with different plugins for page building.

INTEREST



TEACHING



PHOTO EDITING



PET LOVER







EDUCATION

Dr. APJ ABDUL Kalam University, Lucknow 2014-18

B. Tech in Computer Science and Engineering from Raj Kumar Goel Engineering College, Ghaziabad (72.3%).

Kendriya Vidyalaya, Balrampur (C.B.S.E) 2012-14

- Matriculation in 2012 and passed with 9.2 C.G.P.A
- Intermediate in 2014 and passed with 73%.

ACHIEVEMENT

Google India challenge scholarship Feb 2018

Frontend Developer Course from Udacity for Phase Ist.

PAST PROJECTS

Chrome Data (Website & Panel)

Organization: Terasol Technologies

Technologies: HTML, SCSS, Bootstrap 4, JavaScript & PHP

Role: Frontend Development

Description:

- Developed the website for selling analytical data
- Custom Panel for uploading large .csv files and viewing/updating them.

Hosted Link (staging version): http://site.chromedm.com/chrome-website/

Panda Clean (Website & Android App Using Cordova)

Organization: Terasol Technologies

Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript & PHP (REST API'S)

Role: Frontend Development / App Developer

Description:

- The application purpose is to provide all types of car services.
- The app helps users to find nearby Mechanics, products etc.

App Link (Beta version):

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.terasoltechnologies.pandaclean

REFERENCES

Terasol Technologies Pvt. Ltd.

Mr. Sanjay Pandey +91-8285826486

Creative Directive

Email: sanjay.pandey@terasol.in

Address: Office 69-70, Ecotech Complex Above Building Material Market, Main Rd, Ecotech-II, Udyog Vihar, Greater Noida, Uttar Pradesh 201306 Terasol Technologies Pvt. Ltd.

Mrs. Aparajita Roy +91-8800600776

Human Resource Strategist Email: aparajita.roy@terasol.in

Address: Office 69-70, Ecotech Complex Above Building Material Market, Main Rd, Ecotech-II, Udyog Vihar, Greater Noida, Uttar Pradesh 201306

ASSETS

- Consistent, Self-discipline, optimistic
- Sprit of team work and leadership qualities
- Adaptability and decision-making abilities

PERSONAL DETAILS

Father's Name: Mr. Rai Chandra Gupta

Mather's Name: Mrs. Laxmi Devi Gupta

Date of Birth: 08/07/1997

Address H No. 338, Dr. Nawab Clinic, Civil lines,

Balrampur (271201)

facebook.com/imshivamgupta

instagram.com/imshivamgupta_

github.com/imshivamgupta